{
  "reference_number": "10274",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "Focus and invest (financially and technologically) in solar energy: natural, clean, ready made, democratic NUCLEAR FUSION ENERGY,\n WITHOUT NUCLEAR WASTE!"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "We are a small and well educated society who can achieve SOLID RESULTS by ourselves. No paper carbon credits should be involved."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Realistically no one can foresee the future. The target should be revised IF, AND ONLY IF, VERY SPECIFIC CIRCUMSTANCES demand\n the course must be modified"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "However, budgets MUST BE VERY SPECIFIC AND WELL QUANTIFIED. Wordy, electoral speeches will not help with the Climate Change\n issue."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - the third emissions budget should be able to be changed but only when the subsequent budget is set",
      "answer_index": 4,
      "notes": "Serious commitment to the budget. Change of budgets only after a new SPECIFIC AND QUANTIFIED budget is set."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "But only under VERY EXCEPTIONAL CIRCUMSTANCES! Either we are serious and committed to the budgets or we are not. If we are not\n\n let's not waste time and resources."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Without a timeframe the Bill cannot be the basis for emission budgets. Budgets without a timeframe do not exist!"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "The relationship with the country's energy production and distribution structure. For example, emphasis on a serious solar energy\n\nprogramme for domestic use will attract resistance because THE SUN HAS NO SHAREHOLDERS."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Plans and/or budgets without progress monitoring do not exist. That's why the Budgets need to be very specifically QUANTIFIED."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Zero Carbon emissions and Climate Change are inextricably related."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Obviously organisations of strategic relevance should share information on the risks their activities face associated with climate\n\nchange through a regular and structured reporting system."
    }
  ]
}
